onhandrecipes.com 2018-08-25

# OnHandRecipes.com Privacy Policy

At OnHandRecipes we recognize the importance of your privacy. That said, it's understandable that you may be concerned with the information you provide to us and how we use it. With these concerns in mind, we've developed the following Privacy Policy outlined below. We may update this Policy from time to time, so please check back occasionally. If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, you can contact us using this form. 

## Note to children under the age of 13

If you're under 13, you must provide us with written permission from your parents before sending any information about yourself to us over the Internet. 

## Information collected and how it is used

OnHandRecipes.com is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent your information to others in any way different from what is disclosed in this statement. OnHandRecipes.com collects voluntary information from you at several different points on our website. This information is used to enhance your experience on our website, mobile applications and software. 

### I. Registration

OnHandRecipes does not collect your personal identifiable information unless you provide it to us voluntarily and knowingly. This means we don't require you to register or provide information to us in order to view our site. However, you must register if you wish to use certain features on our site. 

During registration you are required to give contact information (such as your name and email address). This information is used to provide the services that you have requested, or to contact you about the service on our site for which you have expressed interest. We may contact you from time to time with news as well as for internal marketing and promotional purposes. 

### II. Recipe submission

Your personally identifying information may be used for editorial purposes (such as attributing your submitted recipe to you). We may also use this information to contact you should we have any complications with your recipe. The visibility of your profile can be restricted by you via your user settings. 

### III. Recipe request

When you subscribe to this feature, we ask for your name and email address and the description of the recipe that you are requesting. OnHandRecipes then posts your name and your recipe description to the site. The email address you provided is only used for us to contact you when your request has been filled. 

### IV. Contest, Promotions and Surveys

You must be a registered user in order to enter contests and promotions on OnHandRecipes.com. Participation in these events is completely voluntary and we do not require you to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as your name and shipping address) and demographic information. Your contact information will be used to notify you if you've won and award prizes. 

From time to time our site may request information from you via surveys. This information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site and participation is completely at your discretion. 

### VI. Cookies 

Like most web sites, we use "cookie" technology on our web site. We may place a "cookie" in the browser file of your computer, however the "cookie" itself does not contain any personally identifying information about you. The "cookie" does not track your personal information or provide us with any way to contact you, and the "cookie" does not extract any information off your computer. We use the "cookie" to provide functional information about your browser, allowing us to provide you a better experience. We also use "cookies" to gather broad demographic information and general usage patterns about you and other users of our sites. 

If your browser rejects cookies, you may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that you will be limited from accessing certain areas of our site, such as contests, coupons, recipe box, shopping list feature, etc. 

Some of our business partners also use cookies on our site. 

OnHandRecipes, and its advertisers and affiliates are deeply committed to protecting the privacy of Internet users. Below is information outlining our continued support for the responsible management of consumer information. 

### Consumer Information

During the process of delivering an ad to you, OnHandRecipes does not collect any personally identifiable information about you such as name, address, phone number, or e-mail address. However, OnHandRecipes does obtain some types of non-personally identifiable information such as the Internet Service Provider you use to connect to the Internet, your browser type, or the type of computer operating system you use (Macintosh or Windows, for example). The information collected by OnHandRecipes.com is used for the purpose of targeting ads and measuring ad effectiveness on behalf of our advertisers. 

In some cases, you may voluntarily provide personal information in response to a specific ad (this ad may ask you to fill out a survey or provide your zip code). If this does occur, OnHandRecipes.com may collect this information on behalf of an advertiser. This information is used by an advertiser to respond to your request. In addition, OnHandRecipes.com combine this information with other users' information and review it in an aggregate form to understand the type of individuals who view a specific type of ad or visit a particular kind of website. 

### Data Collection

OnHandRecipes, as well as most sites on the Internet, use "cookies" or any unique id provided by your device to enhance your experience on the web. OnHandRecipes.com cannot use these cookies to personally identify you in any way. What are cookies and why do we use them? A cookie is a unique number that is provided to you the first time OnHandRecipes.com serves you an ad. This unique number, which is stored in a cookie file on your computer, helps OnHandRecipes.com target ads to you. This cookie can help OnHandRecipes.com ensure that we don't serve you the same ad multiple times, and help our advertisers understand what you like and don't like about their offerings so that they can cater better to your needs the next time you are interested in their products or services. While we believe that cookies enhance your Internet experience by limiting the number of times you see the same ad and delivering more relevant content to you, they are not required for OnHandRecipes.com to deliver you an ad. 

If you do not want the benefit of cookies, there is a simple procedure to manually delete your cookies. Please consult your web browser's Help documentation for more information. 

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). 

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site.

Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet.

Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

Last updated: 2014-12-28

  * Terms of Use
